让我们总结一下我们在本次讲座中学到的内容，并且有一些重要的内容
Let’s summarize what we have learned in this lecture and there are some important
我希望你带回家的消息。第一个也许是最重要的是
messages that I’d like you to take home. The first and perhaps the most important is
机器人是真的。是的，有很多关于机器人的小说，书籍，
that robots are real. Yes, there are many depictions of robots in fiction, in books,
电视和电影，但世界上有许多真正的机器人正在做有用的事情
TVs and movies, but there are a number of real robots in the world doing useful things
马上。接下来的信息是机器人的形式和功能非常多样化。
right now. The next message is that robots are very diverse in their form and their function.
它们看起来不像您熟悉的虚构机器人。我们有
They don’t necessarily look like the fictional robots that you are familiar with. We have
看到了各种各样的现实世界机器人。我们已经看到用于制造的机器人手臂
seen a great diversity of real world robots. We have seen robot arms that are used in manufacturing
植物。我们见过带轮子的机器人。我们见过有腿的机器人。我们见过机器人
plants. We have seen robots with wheels. We have seen robots with legs. We have seen robots
可以飞行，我们已经看到可以在水下或机器人船上移动的机器人
that can fly and we have seen robots that can move under water or robot boats that can
在水面上移动。我们已经研究过可以执行各种不同操作的机器人
move on the surface of water. We have looked at robots that perform a wide range of different
功能。而且，机器人的形状，就是它的形状
functions. And, the form of the robot, that is its shape
它如何在世界范围内移动，在很大程度上取决于它所需要的功能
and how it moves through the world depends very much on the function that it needs to
执行。所以，如果它需要在空中移动，那么它的形式是飞行器，
perform. So, if it needs to move through the air, then its form is of a flying machine,
也许像固定翼飞机或者像直升机一样。如果它必须移动
perhaps like a fixed wing aircraft or perhaps like a helicopter. If it’s got to move across
在湖面上，它会有一个看起来像船的形状。功能
the surface of a lake, then it’s going to have a form that looks like a boat. The functionality
机器人正在迅速改善。如果我们看看制造机器人
of robots is improving very, very rapidly. If we look at manufacturing robots from the
1960年代与现在的机器人相比，现代机器人非常可靠，令人难以置信
1960’s and compare it to a robot today, the modern robot is incredibly reliable, incredibly
准确，价格合理。我们对移动机器人看到了同样的事情。
accurate and built for quite a reasonable price. We see the same thing for mobile robots.
我们看看60年代的StanfordCart或Shakey这样的机器人并将其进行比较
We look at robots like the Stanford Cart or Shakey from the ’60’s and compare that
到今天的谷歌汽车。在大约50年的时间里，这是一个非凡的进步
to a Google car of today. That’s a phenomenal amount of progress in a period of about 50
年份。我希望你接受的另一条消息
years. The other message that I’d like you to take
家庭是机器人是解决我们时代一些非常重要的问题的一部分。
home is that robots are part of the solution to some really important problems of our time.
它们将成为为越来越多的人提供负担得起的医疗保健的关键
They are going to be a key to providing affordable health care to the growing number of people
在我们的星球上。它们将在提供基础的行业中发挥重要作用
on our planet. They are going to be important in industries which supply the fundamental
我们星球上所有人的原材料，即食物，能源和矿物质。他们
raw materials for all the people on our planet, that’s food and energy and minerals. They
在管理和检查所有基础设施方面也将发挥关键作用
will also have a really key role in managing and inspecting all of the infrastructure on
我们现代社会所依赖的。最后，它们在监测中发挥着非常重要的作用
which our modern society depends. Finally, they play a really important role in monitoring
我们所有人生活的星球的健康。出于所有这些原因，机器人技术确实如此
the health of the planet on which we all live. For all of these reasons, robotics is a really
重要的技术。这是今天的一项重要技术。它只会变得更多
important technology. It’s an important technology today. It will only become a more
对未来很重要。
important into the future.